我回家了
I'm home!
我爸是地球上最简单的人
My dad was the least complicated guy on the planet.
他的首要追求永远是舒适
His first order of business was to always be comfortable.
这意味着在门口脱掉长裤
That meant parking his pants at the door.
他的嗜好包括在沙发上睡着
His hobbies included sleeping in his chair...
看《神秘岛》
...Watching "Fantasy island"...
别担心  老板
Oh, don't worry, boss.
在沙发上睡着
...Sleeping in his chair...
对着费城人队大叫
...Yelling at the Phillies...
这算是什么投球
What is that pitch?!
在沙发上睡着
...And sleeping in his chair.
他的为父之道也很简单
Even his parenting style was simple
总是涉及了选择性的词汇
and always involved choice vocab words.
小白痴们  别再这么白痴了
Hey, you morons. Stop being morons.
不敢相信  我养了个白痴
Unreal. I raised a moron.
你为什么总是这么白痴
Why you got to be a moron all the time?
他是个简单的人  说实话  对什么都没兴趣
He wasn't a complicated guy or, frankly, even that interesting.
但隔三差五的
But every once in a while,
他会意外展现出一面
he was accidentally reveal something about himself
会让你觉得你根本不认识他
that would make you feel like you didn't know him at all.
好的  修好了
All right, all fixed.
了不起  你在哪里学的
Wow! Where did you learn how to do that?
军队
Army.
什么  你刚说的是"军队"吗
What? Did you say "Army"?
爸  这是你和卢・里德吗[摇滚歌手]
Dad, is this you and Lou Reed?
对  我们一起做过服务生
Yeah, we, uh, waited tables together.
什么  接着讲
What? Tell me more.
就是这样了
Eh, it was a whole thing.
别走  回来  我想了解你
Wait! Come back! I want to know you!
拉升  拉升
Pull up! Pull up!
飞机要坠毁了
You're gonna crash the plane.
我曾经经历过一次坠机
I was in a plane crash once.
午睡时间到
Nap time.
没错  有些人会吹嘘想当年
Yep, some people glorify the past,
但我爸不会
but not my dad.
对他来说  过去似乎没发生过
To him, it's like it never even happened.
我的天  默里  你不会相信的
Oh, my god, Murray, you're not gonna believe it.
你就读的高中刚才打来电话
I just got off the phone with your old high school.
你的纪录被刷新了
Your record has been broken.
慢着  爸读高中时还有纪录吗
Whoa, wait. Dad had a record in high school?
什么样的纪录
What kind of record?
辣椒酱  他爱辣椒酱
Chili! He loves chili.
肯定是和辣椒酱有关的
It's something to do with chili.
他的确喜欢  但不是的
True, but that's not it.
你爸创下了中心高中的
Your dad set the record for most free throws in a row
连续罚球纪录
at Central High.
篮球吗  说什么呢
Like, in basketball? W-what are you talking about?
叫我怎么说  我们赢了州比赛
What can I say? We won state.
我连着进了79个的罚球
Uh, I hit 79 free throws in a row.
你想我怎样
Uh, what do you want from me?
默里  高中想请你回去
Murray, the high school wants you to go back
这样周六晚的比赛  他们可以向你致敬
so they can honor you at the game Saturday night.
我们要住在市区
We get to stay downtown,
而且还会有宴会
and there's gonna be a banquet.
宴会
A banquet?!
这是食物派对中最高级的
That's the fanciest of all food parties!
我知道  这是大事
I know! It's a very big deal.
我是这样想的  不去
Here's the thing about that. Pass.
-不能不去  -不去
- No pass. - Pass!
-我已经说了你会去  -你为什么这样做
- I already told them you'd be there.- Why would you do that?
你知道我对任何事都没兴趣
You know I don't have an interest in things.
这是真的吗
Is this for real?
我们甚至没见过你碰篮球
I mean, we've never even seen you touch a basketball.
真是不敢相信
Yeah, I mean, I can't believe this.
我的梦想之一就是进NBA打球
It's one of my dreams to play in the NBA,
而你却一次也没提过这事
and you never once mentioned it?
没看出来有什么关系
Didn't see how it was relevant.
关系可大了
Oh, it's relevant.
你打算怎么做  你打算怎么做
What you gonna do? What you gonna do?
跟现在做的差不多
Not much more than what I'm doing right now.
我想看看你的水平  罚球帝
I want you to show me what you got, free-throw king!
完事了吗
Are we, uh, done here yet?
不  你显然是受欢迎的高中大神
No! You were clearly some type of popular high school god.
告诉我是什么样子的
Tell me what it was like.
不知道  我约会了不少姑娘
I don't know. I, uh, dated a lot of girls.
我参加了不少派对
I went to parties.
我当选了几次班长
I got elected class president a few times.
午餐大婶免费请我吃果冻
Lunch lady gave me free jell-o.
很平常
Eh, the usual.
不平常  这完全与我的生活相反
Not usual. That's the opposite of my life.
午餐大婶说我
The lunch lady said
看起来像烧了她村子的军阀
I look like the warlord who burnt down her village.
-我进去了  -不  等等  拜托
- I'm going in. - No, wait, wait! Come on!
我以为你要给我指点两下
I thought you were gonna give me some pointers.
除非你想让我指点你两下
Unless you want me to give you some.
三分线以外怎么样
How about from way downtown?
希望你带了伞
Hope you brought an umbrella,
因为要下三分球雨了
'cause it's about to rain some 3s!
进啊  宝贝
Swish, baby!
基本功
Fundamentals!
无形资产[指意志力等等]
Intangibles!
无私
Unselfish!
篮球
Basketball!
投篮就是要这样
And that's how you do it.
你好吗  拉克茜・布鲁姆
'sup, Lexy Bloom?
想在这本新年鉴上签下第一笔吗
Ready to break the seal on this new yearbook, or what?
好的
Uh, sure.
这一年  巴瑞把整个年鉴留空
This year, Barry left an entire page blank
只为了一个他在乎的签名
for the one signature he cared about --
他的梦中女孩  拉克茜・布鲁姆
His dream girl, Lexy Bloom.
暑假玩得开心哦  古斯塔夫
"Have a bitchin' summer, Gustav"?
我不是瑞典交换生
I'm not the swedish exchange student!
我跟你说的可是英语
I'm speaking english to you!
挥棒落空
Swing and a miss.
你爱她  她却以为你是从瑞典来的
Aw, you love her, and she thinks you're from Sweden.
我这一整年都在努力打出自己的名号
I've spent all year trying to make a name for myself,
但拉克茜・布鲁姆依然不知道我是谁
and Lexy Bloom still doesn't know who I am.
她真幸运
She's so lucky.
如果能有一种办法  能和全校最酷的学生
If only there was a way to, like, have a casual get-together
随意地聚在一起
with the coolest kids from school,
比如说在我们家
like, at our house,
但没有正式的晚宴
but without the formal, sit-down dinner.
我想你说的是派对
I think you're describing a party.
我的天  我有一个好棒的主意
Oh, my god. I have the greatest idea.
我要办一个派对
I'm gonna throw a party.
爸妈周六晚在市区
Mom and dad are staying downtown Saturday night.
我要邀请全校的人
I'll invite the whole school!
先别激动
Whoa, hold on.
-我要你好好想想  -高中朋友们
- Uh, I want you to think about this -- - High-school friends!
这个周六晚
This Saturday night,
我邀请你们参加有史以来
I'm inviting you to the best party
威廉・佩恩高中最棒的派对
in the history of William Penn Academy,
举办人正是在下
thrown by yours truly!
我们爱你  古斯塔夫
We love you, Gustav!
不  我是巴瑞・金伯格
No! I'm Barry Goldberg!
没关系  我家办派对
Doesn't matter! Party at my place!
接下来几天
For the next few days,
巴瑞在全校范围内散布消息
Barry spread the word all over school.
到时一定是个狂野派对
It was gonna be a wild rager,
没人比我更激动了
and nobody was more excited than me.
老天  我的第一场高中派对
Oh, man. My first high-school party
R级语言  成人场景
with r-rated language and adult situations.
这是我自己的《乖仔也疯狂》
This is my "Risky Business."
太对了
Damn right!
到时会有跳舞  打架
There's gonna be dancing, fistfights,
披萨在唱片机上
pizzas on record players,
漂亮啦啦队员从屋顶上跳进泳池里
hot cheerleaders jumping from the roof into the pool.
咱家没有游泳池
We don't have a pool.
没有吗
Don't we?
吹起来
Blow this up.
太棒了
Sweet!
我去拿哮喘吸入器  这就开始吹
I'm gonna go grab my inhaler and get started.
好了
Okay!
我这里有扭扭乐和烟灰缸
I got twister and ashtrays.
派对什么时候开始
What time's this party kicking off?
慢着  你没意见吗
Whoa, wait. You're okay with this?
我不认同对你父母撒谎
Uh, look, I-I don't condone lying to your parents,
但我看着你这年起起伏伏
but I've been tracking your highs and lows this year.
说实话  你需要这个
And frankly, you need this.
太棒了
Awesome!
现在只剩下确保
Only thing left is to make sure
爸妈走的时候不疑心就行了
mom and dad leave without suspecting a thing.
好了  我的宝贝
Okay, love bugs.
我们晚上不在  你们得听老爷子的
Pops is in charge while we're away for the evening.
玩得开心
Have fun.
怎么会开心
No fun here.
我们会坐在这里闷到死
We're just gonna sit here bored to death
等你们回家
waiting for you to come home.
这样的话  穿上鞋子跟我们走
Oh, well, in that case, throw on some shoes and join us!
就这样定了
I insist.
那就这样  我们也去
Then it's settled. We're coming.
-你做什么 -我慌了
- What are you doing? - Panicking.
如果孩子们一起去  我就留家里
Okay, if the kids come with us, I'm staying home.
太好了  留下
Great! Stay.
你什么毛病啊
What's wrong with you?!
人越多越好
The more the merrier.
你真是个超级蠢的笨蛋
You're a stupid, stupid boy.
你们去吧  这里有我
Y-you two just go. I'll hold down the fort.
-好吧  -晚餐在冰箱里
- All right. - Dinner's in the fridge.
好险啊
That was a close one.
我们合作得太棒了
We make a good team, guys.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
巴瑞等不及他的史诗经典夜开始时
While Barry couldn't wait to start his epic night,
我爸依然对他的漠不关心
My dad was still indifferent about his...
1961年州冠军队的队长
...Captain of the 1961 state championship team
默里・金伯格
Murray Goldberg!
直到他看到这一幕
...Until this happened.
这是怎么啦
What the hell's going on?
这些人什么毛病啊
What's wrong with these people?
没什么  他们爱你 默里
Nothing -- they love you, Murray.
对我爸来说  过去已经过去了
For my dad, the past was the past.
他从来不想
He never wanted to be
做那种总是追忆当年辉煌的人
one of those guys always recounting his glory days.
但在那闪耀的时刻  他决定拥抱过去
But for one shining moment, he decided to embrace it.
加油  海狸们  加油
Let's go, beavers! Let's go!
咬咬咬
Chomp, chomp, chomp!
我爸多年没碰篮球了
My dad hadn't picked up a basketball in years.
但上半场结束时
But by the end of the first half,
他已经整装待发了
he was ready to suit up.
篮球就是这样打的  海狸们
That's how we do it, beavers!
太棒了
Yeah!
在这里简短说几句
Just want to take a quick moment
欢迎默里・金伯格回到母校
to welcome back Murray Goldberg.
为纪念他25年的纪录
In honor of his 25-year-old record,
我们要送给他
we'd like to present him
这个全队签名的篮球
with a ball signed by the entire team.
默里  过来吧
Murray, come on down.
嘿  高手
Hey, hot stuff!
谢谢  太感谢了
Thank you. Thank you very much.
射篮  射篮  射篮
Shoot the ball! Shoot the ball! Shoot the ball!
射篮  射篮
Shoot the ball! Shoot the ball!
不是吧  你做什么呢
Really? What are you doing?
射篮  射篮
Shoot the ball! Shoot the ball!
那是我老公
That's my husband!
我爸站到罚球线的那一刻
The moment my dad stepped to that line,
他意识到他依然是高中时的那个少年
he realized he was still that kid from high school --
运动员  传奇  冠军
An athlete, a legend, a champion.
结果  他这样做了
and then, he did this.
拍到了
Got it!
你好差劲  老家伙
You suck, old man!
为他说句话  这种罚球方式在他年轻时
In his defense, that was a very common shooting style
非常流行
back in the day.
但随着"三不沾"的嘘声响彻体育馆
But as the chant of "Air ball" rang through the gym,
只是证明了我爸
it only confirmed to my dad
不属于这个球场
that he didn't belong on that court.
他的归属是穿着内裤  坐在电视机前
He belonged in front of the tv in his underpants.
但这还不是当晚最尴尬的一幕
But this wasn't the most embarrassing display of the evening.
最尴尬的还是我哥史诗经典的派对
That belonged to my brother's epic party.
已经九点了
It was 9:00,
到场的人只有我
and the only people that showed up were me,
罗杰・麦克法登  他带了妙脆角来
Roger Mcfadden, who brought bugles,
还有外国交换生  古斯塔夫
and Gustav, the foreign-exchange student.
回见  我出去了
Later. I'm going out.
慢着  慢着
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
看那里
Look -- look what's happening in there.
全男生聚会
It's a pure sausage fest.
妙脆角只有漂亮女生才可以吃
The bugles are for hot chicks only!
你是个受欢迎的女生  请一些你的朋友过来
You're a popular girl. Invite some of your friends over.
那可怜的家伙需要这场派对
The poor guy needs this.
闭嘴  古斯塔夫
Shut up, Gustav!
这叫做恰到好处的姗姗来迟
It's called being fashionably late.
好吧  我打电话给几个朋友
Fine. I'll call a couple of my friends.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在  这事一个推特就能搞定
Nowadays, all it would take is a tweet.
但那时  一个电话也同样能搞定
But back then, one phone call worked just as well.
你不是说几个朋友吗
I thought you said "A couple of friends."
我就打给了兰妮
All I did was call Lainey.
你想要巴瑞玩得开心对吗
You wanted Barry to have fun, right?
瞧瞧他  完全是大人物
Look at the guy. He is the man.
欢迎来到巴瑞的家  女士们
Welcome to casa de Barry, ladies!
气色不错  裤子很不错嘛  不认识的哥们
Looking good. Nice pants, random dude.
告诉过你我能行的
Told you I'd rock.
这场派对完全就像是饶舌歌MTV对吗
Is the party like a rap video, or what?
一边凉快去  罗斯姨妈的50大寿
Move over, aunt Rose's 50th.
这是咱家餐厅见识过的最热闹的派对
This is the hottest party this dining room's ever seen.
我的妈呀  是拉克茜・布鲁姆
Holy crap. It's Lexy Bloom.
她来了
She came!
她在这里
She's here!
你还在等什么  老哥
What are you waiting for, man?
扔颗口香糖
Chiclet me.
美女
Whoa, girl.
看来你找到了贵宾区
I see you found the V.I.P. Section.
为什么这里是贵宾区
What makes this the V.I.P. Section?
因为我在这里
'cause I'm here.
你要什么  我就能提供什么
Anything you want, I'll make it happen.
水果卷  百吉饼
Fruit roll-ups? Bagel bites?
摩登原始人牌维生素片
Flintstone vitamins?
你想要什么都有  亲爱的
The world's your oyster, baby.
看见没
See?
我们刚给了你奇怪的弟弟
We just gave your weird little brother
他人生中最美好的一晚
the best night of his life.
本大爷来了
Whoo! The party has arrived!
你和他同校吗
You go to school with him?
没有
I do not.
情况失控了
And we're out of hand.
谁要去冲澡
Who wants to take a shower?
十点时  巴瑞的派对气氛爆发了
By 10:00, Barry's party was blowing up...
但没有我姐爆发得那么厉害
But not as much as my sister.
住手  撒得到处都是
Hey! Stop! You're spilling everywhere!
你们两个
You!
不准在我爸的沙发上亲热
Stop making out in my dad's chair!
这是他的栖息地
He lives there!
搞什么  这是我妈妈的
What the hell?! That's my mom's!
为什么你穿着
Why are you wearing that?
这是场毛衣派对
Oh, it's a sweater party.
根本没这回事
That's not a thing.
我在楼梯上挂了"禁止入内"的标语
And I put a sign on the stairs that said "Off limits."
挂着的线断了
Ah, yeah, that piece of yarn broke,
所以我们就不客气了
so we all just kind of... Helped ourselves.
我们
"We"?
脱下  所有人脱下
Off! Everyone take it off!
太棒了  终于发生了  快脱下
Yes! It's happening! Take it off!
亚当  上楼去
Adam, go upstairs!
标语上写着"禁止入内"
Well, the sign says it's off limits.
线断了  给我上楼
The yarn is broken. Upstairs.
我说了上楼
I said "Upstairs"!
好了  局面正式失控了
Okay. This is officially nuts.
你要结束这一切
You need to put an end to this.
我  你才是成年人
Me?! You're the adult!
我是酷外公  我不能做扫兴鬼
I'm the cool grandpa. I can't be the bummer.
你做扫兴鬼
You be the bummer.
有块披萨在唱片机上
Uh, there's a pizza on the record player.
这样对唱片针可不好
It's bad for the needle.
你们这些人真恶心
You people are disgusting!
你到底在做什么
What the hell are you doing?!
这是场毛衣派对
It's a sweater party.
根本没这回事
That's not a thing!
别再煽风点火  你要结束派对
Stop encouraging this. You need to shut it down.
结束
Shut it down?
不可能  这是我的派对
No way! This is my party.
我说我们要狂欢到黎明
And I say we rage on until the crack of dawn!!
好棒
Yeah!
我说每人捡点垃圾后走人
Well, I say we each pick up one piece of trash and leave!
呸
Boo!
想笑你就笑  够了
Smile all you want. That's it.
我给爸妈住的酒店打电话
I'm calling the hotel where mom and dad are staying.
我明白是怎么回事
I see what this is.
你嫉妒了
You're jealous
因为我办了场有史以来最棒的派对
'cause I've thrown the greatest party of all time.
你好好看看  这不是你的派对
Look around. It's not your party.
这些全是我的朋友
These are all my friends.
喂  艾里
Yo, Ari.
这是谁的派对
Whose party is this?
爱丽卡为那个瑞典小子举办的送别派对
Erica's throwing a going-away party for the swedish dude.
不重要  拉克茜・布鲁姆来了
It doesn't matter. Lexy Bloom's here.
她是来见我的
She came to see me.
是吗
Oh, did she?
巴瑞  等等
Barry, wait.
我不是故意...
I didn't mean to --
刚才不太顺利
That did not go well.
是的
No, it did not.
你为什么这么生我的气
Why are you so mad at me?
我看到你的表情了
I saw the look on your face.
你很激动重返球场
You were thrilled to be back out there on that court.
你知道我为什么不谈过去吗
You know why I don't talk about the past?
我来告诉我
I'm gonna tell you.
因为过去很棒
Because it was great.
我是班长  我是篮球明星
I was class president. I was a basketball star.
我是英雄
I was a hero.
现在我什么也不是
And now I'm just none of those things.
你试过这样投篮吗
Have you ever tried shooting the ball this way?
当年这种投法非常流行
It was a very common shooting style!
结果  我爸不是唯一懊恼至极的人
Turns out, my dad wasn't the only one kicking himself.
巴瑞与成为传奇
Barry's big chance
赢取拉克茜・布鲁姆芳心的重大机会
to become a legend and win over Lexy Bloom
正式吻别了
had literally been kissed goodbye.
怎么啦  古斯塔夫
What's shaking, Gustav?
我倒希望自己是古斯塔夫
I wish I was Gustav.
除了无法接受他带的午餐总是有奇怪的鱼
Except for that weird fish lunch he always brings.
你为什么出来了  不在自己的派对上待着
So, why you out here, missing your own party?
我注意到
Well, it has come to my attention
这是爱丽卡的派对
that this is Erica's party,
我只是个巨大的被大家无视的倒霉蛋
and I'm just a big, giant, invisible bag of suck.
拜托  大家没无视你
Oh, come on. You're not invisible.
你是巴瑞・金伯格  冲午餐大婶发飙的人
You're Barry Goldberg, the guy who freaked out
因为没有布丁了
on the lunch lady because they ran out of pudding.
为什么大家就记得我这件事
Why is that the only thing anyone ever remembers about me?
学校保证了有布丁  但结果没有
Hey, they promised pudding. They had no pudding.
那是黑暗的一天
It was a dark day.
我知道你觉得今年很不顺
Look, I know you feel like this year was a bust,
但你做了不少令人印象深刻的事
but you did a ton of cool stuff --
才艺表演上的空手道
Karate in the talent show.
你参加了摔角队
You're on the wrestling team.
你拍了饶舌MTV
You did that rap video
讲述了摩天轮上的心动故事
about stone cold groovin' on a ferris wheel.
-你喜欢我的饶舌歌  -太好笑了
- You like my rap? - It's hilarious.
你的目的就是要搞笑对吗
Wait, that's what you were going for, right?
是的
Yeah!
你怎么知道我这么多事
How do you know so much stuff about me?
你姐是我最好的朋友
Your sister's my best friend.
我已经认识你一辈子了
I've known you my whole life,
我可以诚实地说
and I can honestly say there's...
你与众不同
No one like you.
谢谢
Thanks.
谁会想到我姐开放的  有着坏影响的最佳损友
Who knew my sister's wild, bad-influence best friend
居然以奇怪的  巴瑞的方式
would be the one to remind my brother that he was special
提醒了我哥他是特别的
in his own bizarre, Barry kind of way?
别再郁闷了
Now stop pouting
进去让爱丽卡的朋友们看看  这到底是谁的派对
and come show Erica's friends whose party it really is.
很长时间以来第一次
For the first time in ages,
对我哥来说有了盼头
things were looking up for my big bro.
但好景不长
It didn't last long.
我的天
Oh, god!
死了
Oh, balls!
大家试着收拾一下
Everybody try and clean up a little bit!
我去睡觉了  大家快逃命吧
I-I'm going to bed! Everyone, run!
巴瑞看着爸妈走下车
As Barry watched my parents get out of that car,
他知道只有一件事可以做
he knew there was only one thing to do --
吓傻掉
Freak out.
妈  爸
Mom! Dad!
你们怎么回来啦
Why are you home?
你们应该待在酒店
You're supposed to be at the hotel!
有宴会啊  谁会错过宴会
There was a banquet! Who skips a banquet?!
派对
A party?!
我连自己的孩子都不喜欢
I don't even like my own kids,
更别说一屋子的陌生人
let alone a house full of other people's!
默里  老天爷  他们穿的是我的毛衣
Murray! Oh, my god. They're wearing my sweaters!
不  那些不是你的
No! Those aren't yours!
现在就流行这样  看看MTV台就知道
It's a look that's happening! Watch MTV!
是啊  我确信所有年轻男生
Yeah, I'm sure all the young boys
现在都穿豹子图案的毛衣
are wearing leopard sweaters.
喂  那是我的豹子
Hey! That's my leopard!
好吧  显然  你们会杀了我
Okay, fine. Clearly, you're gonna kill me, and --
是的  我会的
Yes! Yes, I am!
快点  默里  徒手宰了这不孝子
Do it, Murray. Do it with your hands.
请听我说
Just hear me out, please.
我和你完全不同  爸
I'm nothing like you, dad.
在高中我不是老大
I don't dominate in high school.
我没有保持体育纪录
I don't hold sports records.
大家认识我  只是因为我为布丁发怒了
People only know me 'cause I get angry at pudding.
听我说  你有着辉煌的过去
Listen, you've had your glory days,
听起来棒极了
and they sounded awesome.
但这个  这里的一切
But this, in there,
我最好也就只能做到这样了
this is the best I'm ever gonna do.
宝贝  太可怜了
Oh, boopie. That's so sad.
但你的麻烦可大了
But you are in so much trouble.
但是  好可怜
But...Aww.
我求你们了  这是我的时刻
I'm begging you. This is my moment.
我只要求
All I'm asking for
再多七个小时的连续派对
is seven more hours of nonstop partying.
当然不行
Absolutely not.
你有十分钟
You got 10 minutes.
-真的吗  -就当帮我一个忙
- Seriously? - Yeah, but do me a favor.
让今晚成为你永生难忘的夜晚
Make this a night you'll always remember.
你是地球上最好的父亲
You are the greatest father on this planet.
我哥拼命地冲向
As my brother desperately sprinted off
他十分钟的辉煌时
for his 10 minutes of glory,
我爸意识到  他依然可以做
my dad realized he could still be a hero
对他来说真正重要之人的英雄
to someone who actually mattered.
糟糕的为父之道
Awful parenting choice.
糟糕透了
Just awful.
你也看到他跑步的样子了  他需要这个
You've seen him run. He needs this.
就是这样  巴瑞的学年进入了尾声
This was it -- Barry's year was coming to a close,
以最后的神奇十分钟谢幕
and it all came down to 10 magical minutes.
他知道只有一种方法留下自己的标志
He knew there was only one way to leave his mark.
那就是在舞池上
That was on the dance floor.
虽然他与迈克尔・杰克逊相距甚远
He may have been a far cry from Michael Jackson.
但在那一刻  他觉得自己杰克逊附体了
But in that moment, he sure felt like him.
让大家围拢来的
It wasn't just Barry's enthusiasm
不仅是巴瑞的热情
that brought the crowd together.
还有他那巨大的80年代录音机
It was his giant '80s boom box
大声唱出了我们青春的圣歌
blasting out the anthem of our youth.
听起来是这样的
And it sounded like this.
我们一定会成功
Oh, we're halfway there
活在祈祷中
Whoa, livin' on a prayer
牵着我的手
Take my hand
我发誓  我们一定会成功
We'll make it, I swear
活在祈祷中
Whoa, livin' on a prayer
那家伙是谁
Who is that guy?
那是巴瑞・金伯格  这是他的派对
That's Barry Goldbg. This is his party.
兄弟  拉克茜・布鲁姆看着这边
Dude, Lexy Bloom's looking over here.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
我会帮你  你想让她嫉妒吗
I'm gonna help you out. You ready to make her jealous?
让她什么
Make her what?
你做什么
What are you doing?
好痛  我不知道  你做什么
Ow! I don't know! What are you doing?
这是我这辈子最美好的夜晚
This is the greatest night of my life!
时间到  滚出我的家
Times up! Get the hell out of my house!
留下我的毛衣
And leave my sweaters!
自然而然  我哥被禁足整个暑假
Naturally, my brother was grounded for the entire summer.
你要把我所有的毛衣拿去干洗
And you get to take all my sweaters to the dry cleaners.
但有时候
But sometimes,
为了那神奇的时刻  怎样都值得
those magic moments are worth it.
我非常生气  你胆子真不小  年轻人
I'm very upset. You have a lot of nerve, young man.
那是他将永生铭记的一晚
It was a night he'd carry with him forever,
没人可以夺走的一晚
A night no one could take away.
在那短暂的一刻
For one brief moment,
巴瑞・金伯格是个传奇
Barry Goldberg was a legend.
你想听听  我是怎么认识卢・里德的吗
Y-you want to hear about, uh, how I met Lou Reed?
想
Uh, yeah.
好的  那是1965年
Okay. It was 1965...
当然  我爸永远会是那种
Sure, my dad would always be the kind of guy
喜爱电视和懒人沙发的人
who loved his tv and his la-z-boy.
但在那命中注定的一晚后
But after that fateful night,
他觉得敞开心扉容易些了
he found it easier to open up a bit more.
进啊  宝贝
Swish, baby!
据我计算
Okay, by my count,
你之前22球全没投进
you've missed the last 22 shots.
按我的方式投一次吧
Just do it my way once.
好吧
Fine.
进啊  宝贝
Swish, baby!
新的投篮方式
New shooting style!
更疯狂的是
And, even crazier,
巴瑞让我爸  罚球帝
Barry got my dad, the free-throw king...
重返球场给他一些指导
...Back on the court for some actual pointers.
无形资产
Intangibles!
但帮助不大
It didn't help much.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
你长得这么可爱  球技多烂也没关系
You're delicious no matter how bad you are.
见鬼  巴瑞
Oh, damn it, Barry!
说到我的童年
When it comes to my childhood,
也许我并不能总记得
I may not always remember...
事情发生的具体时间
...exactly when something happened,
或是参与者都有谁
or exactly who was there.
但我知道  那是一九八几年
But I do know that it was 1980-something
超级棒的金色年代
and it was awesome.
别再拍了  出去  妈
Stop videotaping! Get out! Mom!
献给我真正的家人
别拍了  我发誓...
Stop! I swear...
致命一击  致命一击
Death blow. Death blow.
你把我给惹火了  小兔崽子
You're aggravating me, you little bastard!
他把我给惹火了  小兔崽子
He's aggravating me, the little bastard!
你为什么要打自己
Why are you hitting yourself, huh?
你脸怎么你啦
What did your face ever do to you?
打开
Open up.
不  就不  就不
No! No! No! No! No!
就不  就不
No. No. No. No.
我的天  这个家真是疯了
My god. This house is going nuts.
这个家真是疯了
This house is going nuts.
我是擎天柱
I am optimus prime,
我是好人  我会打败你
and I am a good guy, and I will kick your butt!
谁啊
Who's there?
快换好衣服
Get dressed now!
Get dressed now.
就是这样了
And this is it.
啊  好痛
Aah! That hurt! Aah!
真是疯狂的一晚
Whoa, what a night.
还好吗  有没有橙汁
What's up? You got any O.J.?
不好意思  你在这里做什么
I'm sorry, what the hell are you doing here?
派对上我醉倒在地下室了
Ah, I passed out in the basement during the party.
脱下我的毛衣后出去
Take off my sweater and get out.
-我有什么好处  -没有  这是我的毛衣
- What's in it for me? - Nothing. It's my sweater.
好吧
Fine.
-给我看咪咪  -不
- Show me your boobs. - No!
-给我一百万  -不
- Then give me $1 million. - No.
我想重启咪咪话题
I'd very much like to revisit the boob conversation.
[贝弗莉帮默里拿回沙发那次]
我觉得我们有过一次这样的对话
I feel like we've done this once before.
-最后我看到了咪咪吗  -没有
- Did it end in boobs? - No.
告诉我
Tell me something.
你最后一次吃营养均衡的早餐是什么时候
When was the last time you had a balanced breakfast?
每一天
Every day.
牛肉干提供蛋白质  糖霜提供能量
Protein from beef jerky, energy from frosting.
亲爱的  坐下吧  我帮你做吃的
Sweetie, sit down. I'm gonna make you some food.
你吃完后
You're gonna eat it.
脱下我的毛衣  给我走人
Then you're gonna take off my sweater and get the hell out.
早啊  巴瑞
Morning, Barry.